Dave Zhenyu Chen

I28 Visual Computing GroupTechnical University of MunichBoltzmannstr. 385748, Garching B. Munich, Germany

Email: zhenyu.chen@tum.de Phone: +49 162 5180873

Website:

https://daveredrum.github.io/

Research Areas

My research interests lie in the joint understanding of object semantics in 3D physical world and natural language. Specifically, I'm interested in 1) 3D scene understanding, e.g. 3D semantic/instance segmentation; 2) Grounding natural language in 3D environments; 3) Text-to-3D generation.

Publications

ECCV '22

D3Net: A Unified Speaker-Listener Architecture for 3D Dense Captioning and Visual Grounding. *Dave Zhenyu Chen*, Qirui Wu, Matthias Nießner, Angel X. Chang

CVPR'21

Scan2Cap: Context-aware Dense Captioning in RGB-D Scans. **Dave Zhenyu Chen**, Ali Gholami, Matthias Nießner, Angel X. Chang

ECCV '20

ScanRefer: 3D Object Localization in RGB-D Scan using Natural Language.

Dave Zhenyu Chen, Angel X. Chang, Matthias Nießner

In submission

Text2Tex: Text-driven Texture Synthesis via Diffusion Models.

Dave Zhenyu Chen, Yawar Siddiqui, Hsin-Ying Lee, Sergey Tulyakov, Matthias Nießner

In submission

UniT3D: A Unified Transformer for 3D Dense Captioning and Visual Grounding. **Dave Zhenyu Chen**, Ronghang Hu, Xinlei Chen, Matthias Nießner, Angel X. Chang

Education

Ph.D. [2019 -]

Technical University of Munich (TUM), Germany

Topic: Bridging 3D Physical World and Natural Language

Advised by Prof. Dr. Matthias Nießner and Prof. Dr. Angel X. Chang

M.Sc. [2016 - 2018]

Ludwig Maximilian University of Munich (LMU), Germany Major: Informatics; GPA: 1.59/1.00 (Top 5%, low is good)

Thesis: 3D Shape Captioning via Self-attentional Cross-Modal Joint Embedding

B.Eng. [2012 - 2016]

University of Electronic Science and Technology of China (UESTC), China

Major: Computer Science; GPA: 3.75/4.00 (Top 10%)

Research Experience

Visiting Student Researcher [2022.2 - 2022.5]

Simon Fraser University (SFU), Canada Mentor: Prof. Dr. Angel X. Chang

Ph.D. Candidate [2019.2 -]

Technical University of Munich (TUM), Germany

Advisor: Prof. Dr. Matthias Nießner and Prof. Dr. Angel X. Chang

Research Intern [2018.11 - 2019.2]

Technical University of Munich (TUM), Germany

Mentor: Prof. Matthias Nießner Worked on cross-modal retrieval for 3D shapes

Services

Journals & Conferences

Reviewer

CVPR, ECCV, ICCV, ICRA, IJCV, WACV, 3DV, TVCG.

Workshops

Organizer

 2^{nd} Language for 3D Scenes Workshop, ECCV 2022 1^{st} Language for 3D Scenes Workshop, CVPR 2021

Teaching

Teaching Assistent

Advanced Deep Learning for Computer Vision, 2019-2023, TUM

Practial Course: Big Data Science, 2018, LMU

Skills

Programming Tools

Python, JavaScript, C/C++, Java, Shell, HTML, 图形X

PyTorch, TensorFlow, OpenCV, Blender

Language

Chinese (native), English (C1), German (B2)

References

Prof. Dr. Matthias Nießner

Professor, TUM niessner@tum.de

http://www.niessnerlab.org/index.

html

Prof. Dr. Angel X. Chang

Assistent Professor, Simon Fraser University angelx@sfu.ca

https://angelxuanchang.github.io/

Last update: Mar 22, 2023